# ERIK EMOND

 $\bowtie$ 

erik.emond@gmail.com

C

347-683-7333

9

Stroudsburg, PA 18360

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative, collaborative film/video editor with 15+ years experience. All of that time spent working with many great agencies and clients in the NYC advertising industry. Freelance editing for the past 10 of those years and currently looking to branch out to find new creative collaborations. Efficient and reliable with passion for bringing creative projects to fruition.

### **SKILLS**

- Video Editing
- · Adobe Premiere
- Avid Media Composer
- Sound Design
- Music Integration
- Adobe After Effects
- Online Content
  Development
- · Complex Problem-Solving
- English Fluent
- Links:
- https://www.linkedin.com /in/erok73/
- http://erikemond.com/

#### **EDUCATION**

City College of New York New York, NY

Film

Suffolk County Community College

Selden, NY • 05/1995

Associate of Arts

#### **WORK HISTORY**

Freelance - Film Editor

New York, NY • 07/2013 - Current

- Short form film editor working mostly in advertising, who has worked on many different forms of content
- Worked with all sorts of clients from McDonald's, to Verizon and Disney
- Worked inside of many different Agencies and Post Houses during my time as a freelancer
- Created short-form videos, animated gifs and motion graphics for social media posts
- Created titles, captions, graphics and templates in After Effects to give edits additional visual flare

### Outside Editorial - Film Editor

New York, NY • 06/2008 - 07/2013

- One of a small group of film editors working in this boutique editorial company
- Worked with many big clients over the years including Old Navy, Lenovo, Rock Star Games and Dos Equis
- Conceived, crafted and executed dynamic video edits to captivate target audiences and accomplish project objectives

#### Freelance - Junior Editor

New York, NY • 01/2006 - 06/2008

 Worked with several edit houses honing my skills as I was about to become a full time editor

- Collaborated with writers, designers and other editors to deliver content of highest quality
- Suggested improvements to content to enhance quality and accuracy

# Chickonkey - Assistant Editor

New York, NY • 01/2004 - 12/2005

- Worked as an assistant editor for a boutique editorial house in order to sharpen my skills
- Worked with graphic artists, post-production team members and other specialists to produce captivating and successful content
- Acquired in-depth knowledge of content areas to provide effective edits

# RCN Entertainment - Assistant Editor/Editor/Post New York, NY • 01/2002 - 12/2003

- Mostly worked as an assistant on documentary TV shows and Reading Rainbow, but I was also given editorial opportunities for their small cable network called ITTV
- Segued into post producing before I ultimately went back into the advertising realm
- Collaborated with writers, designers and other editors to deliver content of highest quality

## **Crew Cuts - Assistant Editor**

New York, NY • 11/1999 - 08/2001

- Crew Cuts was my first editorial job
- Learned a lot from some of the industry's best at a much different time in advertising
- Learned to work with big clients such as Pepsi and FedEx and took a lot away from it